As times change, difficult cases increase in number!
تتضاعف القضايا المعقّدة مع مضيّ خط الوقت
Let's review the double-murder during the intro song!
!قضيّة مرعبة لقي فيها اثنان حتفهما !لنراجع الأحداث مع عزف الشارة
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
We were invited to Yotsui Reika's birthday party.
دُعيت مع ران والعمّ لحفلة عيد ميلاد ابنة أحد الأثرياء الوحيدة، يوتسوي ريكا
Someone punctured everyone's tires,
ثقب شخصٌ مجهول إطارات سيّارات الجميع
forcing us all to wait in the lodge until morning.
فأُجبرنا مع ريكا ومجموعة بقيت معها على الانتظار في المنزل حتّى الصباح لتأتي سيّارة وتقلّنا
That night, while searching for the missing Reika,
،في تلك الليلة، أثناء بحثنا عن ريكا المفقودة
Nikaido was drowned in the fountain.
وجدنا نيكايدو ميتاً غرقاً في النافورة
Ran was similarly attacked, but managed to survive.
وتعرضت ران بدورها لهجومٍ مشابه، لكنّها نجت بشكلٍ ما
Judging from the killer's power outage trick,
،من حيلة قطع الكهرباء للقاتل
it was definitely someone in the mansion!
!فقد كان بين المتواجدين في المنزل بلا شك
Just then, Reika was found drowned to death
وبعدها، وجدنا ريكا ميتة غرقاً
in a bathtub!
!في حوض استحمام
"The Wealthy Daughter Murder Case (Part 2)."
جريمة قتل الابنة الثريّة (الجزء الثاني)
How did this happen to her?!
!كيف حلّ هذا بالآنسة؟
She was drowned.
ماتت غرقاً
I can't say anything without examining
لا يمكنني الجزم قبل فحص
the water she swallowed,
الماء الذي ابتلعته
but her head was probably held underwater.
لكن حُبِس رأسُها تحت الماء للموت غالباً
Which means that Nikaido-san's drowning,
ما يعني أنّ غرق نيكايدو-سان عند النافورة
Ran's near-drowning in the kitchen sink,
وغرق ران الوشيك في مغسلة المطبخ
and this murder were all done the exact same way.
وهذه الجريمة تحمل النهج نفسه تماماً
Then that means!
...مستحيل... أيعني ذلك
These really are--
...إنّها جرائم قتل
...random murders!
!عشوائية
Most likely. And the killer is rather cruel, too.
على الأرجح، والقاتل متحجّرٌ أيضاً
Look. Even her skirt and socks are sopping wet--
انظروا، تنورتها وجواربها مبللة تماماً
evidence that she put up quite a struggle.
دلي>>>لٌ على مقاومتها قبل مقتلها
Poor woman...
يا للمسكينة
There are also rope marks on her wrists
كما توجد آثار تقييد على معصميها
and a tape mark over her mouth.
وشريط لاصق على فمها
It would seem she was kept somewhere
يبدو أنّها اُحتجزت في مكان
prior to being killed.
قبل أن يتمّ قتلها
Who would do something this terrible?
مـ-من قد يُقدم على أمر بهذه الفظاعة؟
Say, you three went to the bathroom just now, right?
ذهبتَ يا إيتشييدا-سان وغوجو-سان مع يوني-سان للحمّام قبل قليل، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أجل
Did you see or hear anything out of the ordinary?
هل رأيتم أو سمعتم شيئاً خارج المألوف؟
No...
كلا
They waited outside while I was in the bathroom,
بينما يدخل أحدنا، كان الآخران ينتظران أمام الحمّام
but there wasn't anything strange.
لكن لم يكن هناك أيّ أمر غريب
Before he went in last, lchieda-san told us to make coffee,
قبل دخوله بعدنا في النهاية، طلب منا إيتشييدا-سان إعداد القهوة فذهبنا للمطبخ
so I don't know about after that...
فلا أعرف ما حصل بعد ذلك
I see.
فهمت
That's how you got your chance to kill her.
هكذا حصلتَ على فرصتك لقتلها
Mifune!
!ميفوني
It takes at least five to six minutes to make coffee.
تحتاج بين خمس لستّ دقائق على الأقل لإعداد القهوة
That's all the time you'd need to take her
يمكنك في تلك المدّة التظاهر بدخول الحمّام
to the bath and kill her.
وأخذ الآنسة التي كنت تحتجزها في مكان لحوض الاستحمام وقتلها يا إيتشييدا
No! I didn't do it!
!كـ-كلا! لم أكن الفاعل
Ichieda-san isn't the killer.
الفاعل ليس إيتشييدا-سان
She's been dead for at least an hour or two.
مضت ساعة لساعتين على الأقل على موت الضحيّة
Meaning she was killed between 5:00 and 6:00.
ما يعني أنّها قُتلت بين الخامسة والسادسة صباحاً
He didn't do it just now.
لم يرتكبها بما أنّه ذهب للحمّام قبل قليل
The same goes for Gojo-san and Yone-san;
ينطبق الأمر على غوجو-سان ويوني-سان
the three of them were with me between 4:00 and 7:00.
فقد كنتم الثلاثة معي بين الرابعة والسابعة طوال الوقت في غرفة المعيشة
This narrows down the list of suspects
ثبات حجج غيابهم يقلّص لائحة المشتبه بهم
to Mifune-san and Rokuda-san, who were in their rooms!
إلى ميفوني-سان وروكودا-سان اللذين كانا في غرفهما في الطابق العلوي
Then it's simple. Rokuda's the killer
الأمر بسيط إذاً، القاتل هو المُسن روكودا
since I didn't do it.
بما أنّه لم يكن أنا
Don't be a fool. I saw you.
لا تكن سخيفاً، لقد رأيتك
At around 6:00 am, you left your room and went somewhere.
غادرتَ غرفتك عند السادسة صباحاً وذهبتَ لمكانٍ ما
Did you, Mifune?!
أ-أفعلت ذلك حقاً يا ميفوني؟
Yeah.
أجل
I got sleepy, so I went upstairs to wash my face.
شعرتُ بالنعاس فذهبت لمغسلة الطابق الثاني لغسل وجهي
A likely story.
أشك في ذلك
The upstairs washroom is right next to the stairs.
مغسلة الطابق الثاني موجودة بجانب الأدراج
You could've killed her on your way there.
كان بإمكانك قتلها في طريقك
What?!
!ماذا؟
Yes, I could have. There's no one to vouch for me.
ربما أمكنني ذلك، فلا شهيد يبرئني
But the same goes for you, too!
!لكن ينطبق ذلك عليك أيضاً
I never saw you while I was up there!
!لم أرك أبداً عندما كنتُ في الأعلى
At any rate, the murder was between 5:00 and 6:00 am.
بأيّ حال، وقعت الجريمة بين الخامسة والسادسة صباحاً
Only you two could've done it.
أي بإمكان أحدكما فقط ارتكابها
If you could kindly tell me what you were doing then...
هلّا أخبرتماني بالتفصيل ما كنتما تفعلانه في ذلك الوقت؟
The old man's right.
العمّ مُحق
She definitely died between 5:00 and 6:00 am.
ماتت بين الخامسة والسادسة بلا شك
Which means those two are the most suspicious.
ما يعني أنّهما الأكثر شبهة
But it's strange.
لكنّ الأمر غريب
Why are her clothes so wet?
لمَ ثيابها بهذا البلل؟
Even if she did fight back, this is too--
...مهما قاومت، هذا كثير
Tape marks...
...آثار شريط
The killer used both rope and tape?!
استعمل القاتل شريطاً لاصقاً مع الحبل؟
Rokuda-san. You didn't leave your room at all?
لم تغادر غرفتك بين الخامسة والسادسة البتّة إذاً يا روكودا-سان؟
That's right.
أجل
And you only left the one time to wash your face?
وأنت يا ميفوني-سان غادرت لغسل وجهك مرّةً فحسب؟
Yeah.
صحيح
Um...
المعذرة
Where exactly was Reika-sama being held?
أين كانت تُحتجز الآنسة بالضبط؟
Doesn't it seem strange? We searched the whole place!
أليس الأمر غريباً؟ فقد قلبنا المكان رأساً على عقب !ولم نجدها أبداً
We searched for her at 10:00.
بحثنا عنها عند العاشرة ليلاً
There wasn't anything in here.
لم يكن هناك شيء في الحمّام وقتها
And the bathtub was empty.
أجل، وكان حوض الاستحمام فارغاً
Was she outside? Maybe in the forest?!
!أكانت في الخارج إذاً؟ أيمكن في الغابة؟
No.
كلا
There's a better place than outside:
يوجد مكان أفضل من الخارج
inside the trunk of one of your cars.
داخل صندوق إحدى سيّاراتكم المركونة أمام المنزل
And you two were the only ones who had
وكنتما المتفرّغين الوحيدين لإخراج ريكا-سان من الصندوق
any time to haul her out from one.
يا ميفوني-سان وروكودا-سان
Looks like one of you is the lunatic
يبدو أنّه أحدكما
who's enjoying these random murders.
القاتل المخبول الذي يستمتع بهذه الجرائم العشوائية
Are these really random, though?
جرائم عشوائية؟ أهي كذلك حقاً؟
Ran was attacked for no reason;
هُوجمت ران بلا سبب
it's only natural to think so.
فمن الطبيعيّ أن يعتقد الجميع ذلك
But why?
لكن لمَ؟
Why did the culprit wait to kill Reika-san
لمَ تريّث القاتل في قتل ريكا-سان
and let us find her only now?!
وتركنا نجدها الآن؟
And it bothers me that she was killed in here.
وما يحيّرني هو مقتلها في حوض الاستحمام هنا
Why didn't the culprit kill her at the fountain
لمَ لم يقتلها في النافورة
instead of locking her in the trunk?
إذا كانت في صندوق السيّارة كما قال العمّ؟
It would be safer and easier than filling a bathtub.
ذلك سيكون بعيداً عن الأنظار، وأسهل من ملء حوض استحمام
What're you doing?!
!ما الذي تفعله؟
Yikes!
!تبّاً
The shower's on! Huh?
إنّه على المروش! ماذا؟
The shower?
المروش؟
Aha! So that's it!
!فهمت! هكذا إذاً
This is a time-based trick!
!هذه حيلة زمن استعملها المجرم
In which case, her unnecessarily wet clothes,
ما يعني أنّ الثياب المبللة فوق الطبيعي
the tape marks, the reason Ran was attacked,
وعلامات الشريط اللاصق على الجثّة، وسبب تعرّض ران للهجوم
and the reason Reika-san's discovery was delayed
،كما الدافع لتأخير كشف جثّة ريكا-سان
all share a common thread!
!كلّ هذه الألغاز مربوطة بخيط
Which means he's the killer!
ما يعني أنّه هو القاتل
He's the bastard who attacked Ran!
!ذاك الوغد هو الذي هاجم ران
But there's no proof that he's the killer!
!لكن لا دليل لديّ، دليل قاطع يدينه
Darn it, isn't there anything?!
!تبّاً، ألا يوجد شيء ؟
Idiot! You wanna get wet that badly?!
!أحمق! أتريد التبلل لهذا الحد؟
Get wet?!
!التبلل؟
That's it! Just maybe--
...فهمت! ربما
For now, let's all move to the living room
لنذهب لغرفة المعيشة حالياً
and wait until the cars arrive.
وننتظر وصول السيّارات لتقلّنا
I'm concerned about Ran, too.
أنا قلقٌ على ران النائمة هناك أيضاً
Not so fast!
!انتظروا
Now what?!
ماذا الآن؟
That wasn't me...
...كلا... لم يكن أنا
Here we go again...
...بدأتْ
What is it, Detective?
ما الخطب حضرة المتحرّي؟
I've figured out who the killer is.
عرفتُ هويّة القاتل
What?!
!ماذا؟
The killer?!
!هويّة القاتل؟
Please remove your coats and toss them this way.
اخلعوا معاطفكم وارموها هنا رجاءً
That will clear all of this up.
سيوضّح هذا كلّ شيء
Stop wasting our time!
!يكفي هراءً
Calm down. Let's just do what he says.
مهلك، لنفعل ما يقوله
He says it'll help determine who the killer is.
فهذا سيساعدنا في تحديد القاتل وفق كلامه
There! Now get checking!
!هيّا، تفقّدها الآن
Now you can figure out who it is, right?!
تستطيع أن تعرف من النظر للمعاطف، صحيح؟
So you are the one responsible
كان أنتَ بالفعل إذاً
for all three incidents at this lodge!
!مُرتكب الثلاث جرائم في هذا المنزل
Yes.
أجل
The one who drowned Nikaido-san in the fountain,
،من أغرق نيكايدو-سان أوّلاً في النافورة
drugged and attempted to drown Ran in the kitchen,
ودسّ حبوباً منوّمة في قهوة ران وحاول إغراقها في المطبخ
and drowned Reika-san in here
ومن أغرق ريكا-سان في حوض الاستحمام هذا
was you, Ichieda-san!
...الفاعل كان
Ichieda. Did you really--
...إيتشييدا، أأنت حقاً من
Stop kidding around, Detective...
!يـ-يكفي مزاحاً حضرة المتحري
Do I look like an insane killer?
هل أبدو كقاتل مخبول؟
Before Nikaido-san was murdered in the first incident,
،قبل مقتل نيكايدو-سان في الحادثة الأولى
we went into the forest to look for Reika-san.
دخلنا الغابة بحثاً عن ريكا-سان المفقودة
The two of you were with him, correct?
كنتما يا روكودا-سان وإيتشييدا-سان معه وقتها، صحيح؟
Yes...
أجل
In the forest, you decided to split up and look for her.
قررتم الانفصال في الغابة والبحث عنها
Ichieda-san followed Nikaido-san
تبع إيتشييدا-سان نيكايدو-سان الذي أصبح بمفرده
and lured him over to the fountain.
واستدرجه للنافورة
He probably said he saw Reika-san by it.
قال شيئاً عن رؤيته لها قرب النافورة غالباً
Then he attacked Nikaido-san from behind
ثمّ هاجم نيكايدو-سان الذي اقترب من النافورة
and drowned him!
!من ورائه وأغرقه
That's just conjecture!
!هذا افتراض فقط
Rokuda-san could've done the same thing!
كان بإمكان روكودا-سان القيام بالأمر نفسه
Besides, why would I attack Ran-san?
كما بترك نيكايدو-سان والآنسة جانباً، لمَ قد أهاجم ران-سان؟
This is the first time I've met her!
!هذه أوّل مرّة ألتقيها
And I was with you when the killer cut the lights
كما عندما قطع المجرم الكهرباء ...لمهاجمة ران-سان
to attack her!
!كنتُ معك
How could I have shut the power off?
كيف لي أن أقطع الكهرباء؟
Don't tell me I had an accomplice...
لا تقل أنّ لديّ شريك
No, you can shut it off easily enough
كلا، أمكنك قطعها آلياً بسهولة دون شريك
by using the air conditioners and microwave ovens!
باستعمال مكيّفات الهواء وآلات المايكرويف
It's easy.
الأمر بسيط
You set the timers on all the air conditioners to the same time,
ضبطت مؤقتات كلّ مكيّفات الهواء على العمل في اللحظة نفسها
and set the microwaves to high.
ورفعت درجة تسخين جهاز المايكرويف في المطبخ لوضعية الفرن
When the time comes, there's a power overload,
سيكون هناك حمل زائد عندما يحين الوقت
which sets off the circuit breakers.
مما يشغّل القواطع
All the timers are still set to 12:30,
والدليل هو بقاء وقت انقطاع الكهرباء على أجهزة تحكّم المكيّفات
and Conan heard something odd after the power failure.
كما سمع كونان صوتاً غريباً عند انقطاعها
Isn't that right?
أليس ذلك صحيحاً يا كونان؟
Yeah! I heard a bell!
!بلى! سمعتُ جرساً
The microwaves here use dials,
،أجهزة مايكرويف هذا المنزل بها أقراص تحكّم
so they still moved without power.
فتحركت حتى دون كهرباء
The microwave was warm when I touched it later,
كما كان المايكرويف دافئاً عندما لمسته لاحقاً
so he has to be right!
فلا شكّ في الأمر
Hey, wait!
!انتظر
You then broke the window to make it
بعد قطعك للكهرباء هكذا، كسرتَ زجاج النافذة في الظلام
look like the killer ran outside
لتوهمنا أنّ القاتل هرب للخارج
and then urged us to make chase.
ودفعتنا للحاق به
You then carried Ran into the kitchen
حملتَ بعدها ران التي أصبحت بمفردها إلى المطبخ
and tried to drown her.
وحاولتَ إغراقها
You had drugged her coffee so she wouldn't fight back.
دسست حبوب منومة في قهوتها قبلاً كيلا تقاوم
Shortly before the power went out,
،قُبيل انقطاع الكهرباء بالأصل
you were in the kitchen with me, looking for Reika-san.
كنتَ في المطبخ معي ونحن نبحث عن ريكا-سان
You could have easily turned the microwaves on
كان بإمكانك بسهولة تشغيل المايكرويف خلسةً
after I left!
!بعدما غادرت
Hold on.
!انتظر قليلاً
Have you forgotten that I have an alibi?
هل نسيت أنّ لديّ حجّة غياب؟
I was with you when Reika-sama was killed!
!كنتُ معك عندما قُتلت ريكا-سان في الحادثة الثالثة
If I'm supposedly behind all three incidents,
،إذا كنتُ المسؤول عن الجرائم الثلاث
then please explain how I killed her.
فوضّح رجاءً كيف قتلتُ الآنسة
He's right.
إيتشييدا-سان محقّ
Reika-sama died between 5:00 and 6:00.
ماتت الآنسة بين الخامسة والسادسة
He was with us the entire time from 4:00 to 7:00.
كان معنا طوال الوقت من الرابعة للسابعة
And the sleeping pills in Ran-san's drink...
،وبالنسبة للحبوب المنومة في قهوة ران-سان
Yone-san brought us that coffee!
يوني-سان كانت من جلبت القهوة
We all chose our own cups!
!اخترنا أكوابنا بأنفسنا
Could he really have planned it in advance?
أكان بإمكانه التجهيز لذلك سلفاً؟
What if he wound up with the drugged coffee?
ماذا لو شرب القهوة المنومة؟
It's simple.
الأمر بسيط
All he had to do was not drink it.
كلّ ما كان عليه فعله هو عدم الشرب
But Ran-san chose her own cup, too.
لكنّ ران-سان اختارت كوبها بنفسها
How could he have predicted that?
كيف أمكنه التكهن بذلك؟
He didn't need to.
لم يكن عليه
Anybody would have done!
!فأيّ شخص كان سيفي بالغرض
So we might've been attacked too?!
!أتقصد أنّه كان قد يهاجمنا أيضاً؟
If you were unlucky enough to drink that coffee.
إذا كنتَ تعيس الحظّ بشرب تلك القهوة، أجل
Had the drug paralyzed you,
عندما يخدّرك العقار
you would've wound up just like Ran.
لا يهم كنتَ رجلاً أم امرأة، كنتَ لتلقى نفس مصير ران غالباً
So you were killing at random?
!كان قتلاً عشوائياً بالفعل إذاً
Stop treating me like a murderer...
تـ-توقفوا عن معاملتي كمجرم
Besides, wouldn't I have killed her
كما كنتُ لأقتلها عند انقطاع الكهرباء
when the power went out?
لو كنتُ مجرماً حقاً، أليس كذلك؟
No, you never intended to kill Ran.
كلا، لم تنو قتل ران من البداية
That's right. It wasn't someone's life you wanted then...
صحيح، لم تسعَ وراء حياة أحد في الحادثة الثانية
...it was testimony!
!بل الشهادة...
You wanted someone to say that their head
أردتَ أن يقول أحد أنّ المجرم حبس رأسه
was held underwater!
!تحت الماء
That would make it seem like the killer
سيجعلنا هذا نعتقد أنّ القاتل استعمل نفس الأسلوب معتمداً على القوّة البدنية في قتل ريكا-سان
drowned the people in all three incidents!
كما الجريمتين السابقتين
So then--
...إذاً
She didn't drown to death?
لم تُغرق الآنسة؟
No, she drowned.
بل أُغرقت
Her head just wasn't held underwater.
لكن لم يُحبس رأسها تحت الماء
Doesn't it seem strange?
ألا تجدون الأمر غريباً؟
Reika-san disappeared at 10:00 pm.
اختفت ريكا-سان عند العاشرة ليلاً
But she was killed between 5:00 and 6:00 am.
لكنّها قُتلت بين الخامسة والسادسة صباحاً
For some reason, the culprit waited seven or eight hours
لسبب ما، انتظر المجرم سبع لثمان ساعات
to kill her.
قبل قتلها
And her clothes wouldn't get that wet,
وثيابها المبللة زيادةً عن اللّزوم
no matter how much she fought back.
مهما قاومت، فلن تتبلل بذاك الشكل
And for some reason, the killer used tape
ولسببٍ ما، استعمل القاتل شريطاً لاصقاً
in addition to the rope.
مع الحبل لتقييد ريكا-سان
The key to all these mysteries...
...مفتاح حلّ كل هذه الألغاز
...is that shower.
!هو المروش
The shower?
المروش؟
Normally, you fill a bathtub using the faucet.
تملأ الحوض بالصنبور عادةً، أليس كذلك؟
But when Conan just tried to use it,
،لكن عندما حاول كونان فتحه قبل قليل
water came out of the shower instead.
خرج الماء من المروش وليس الصنبور
Why was that?
لمَ ذلك؟
It was because the killer used the shower
لأنّ القاتل استعمل المروش
to quietly fill the tub.
لملء الحوض بصمت
He taped her to the tub
،لصق جسدها بالحوض بالشريط
so she would eventually drown.
كي تغرق بنهاية المطاف من تلقاء نفسها مع مرور الوقت
Ichieda-san probably drugged Reika-san
نوّم إيتشييدا-سان ريكا-سان غالباً
when she came down at 10:00,
،عندما نزلت عند العاشرة
carried her in here, and used said trick.
وحملها لحوض الاستحمام واستعمل الحيلة آنفة الذكر
He adjusted the shower so that she would drown
عدّل قوّة المروش كي تغرق
between 5:00 and 6:00 am.
بين الخامسة والسادسة صباحاً
He stayed with us between 5:00 and 6:00,
ثمّ بقي معنا بين الخامسة والسادسة لصنع حجّة غيابه
then pretended to use the bathroom at 7:00
وتظاهر بالذهاب للحمّام عند السابعة
to pull her body out of the tub.
وأخرج جثّة ريكا-سان من الحوض
This crude trick would've seemed obvious
كانت هذه الحيلة الهزيلة لتُكشف
had he not dropped a hint.
لو لم يتّخذ إجراءً إضافياً
A hint?
إجراء إضافيّ؟
Yes. The attack on Ran was meant to make it
أجل، كان الهدف من الهجوم على ران
look like Reika-san's head was held underwater too.
هو جعلنا نعتقد أنّ ريكا-سان قُتلت بحبس رأسها تحت الماء أيضاً
But there was a chance that she might be discovered
لكن تضمنّت هذه الحيلة احتمالاً خطيراً باكتشاف ريكا-سان
inside the bathtub.
في حوض الاستحمام
He burned out the light bulbs here in advance
قطع إنارة مصابيح هذا الجانب سلفاً
to keep people away, but it'd be all over
كي يُبعد الناس، لكن كان أمره سينتهي
if someone checked the tub.
لو تفقّد أحد الحوض
But he overcame this problem by checking the tub himself.
لكنّه حلّ هذه المشكلة بتفقّد الحوض بنفسه
She's not in here.
ليست هنا
Only you could've done this, Ichieda-san!
أي أنّك كنتَ الوحيد القادر على تنفيذ هذه الحيلة يا إيتشييدا-سان
Yes, I would be the most suspicious
صحيحٌ أنّي سأكون الأكثر شبهة
if that trick really was used.
إن اُستعملت هذه الحيلة حقاً
I'll grant you that.
أعترف بذلك
But did you see me do it?
لكن هل رأيتني أفعلها؟
You make some big claims, yet you have no proof...
...إذا لم تملك دليلاً فلا يهم مهما افترضت
That's why I had you remove your coats.
لذا طلبتُ منكم خلع معاطفكم
Then check already!
!تفقّدها إذاً
You won't find anything, though.
لم يكن معطفك ما أردتُ رؤيته
It wasn't your coat that I wanted to see--
!بل بقع الماء على قميصك
it was the water blotches on your shirt!
بقعة الماء على كمّ غوجو-سان
The blotches on Gojo-san's sleeves
كانت من غسيله ليديه في الحمّام
are from when he washed his hands.
والبقعة على ياقة ميفوني-سان
The ones on Mifune-san's collar
كانت من غسيله لوجهه
are from when he washed his face.
ما تفسير البقع في منتصف ذراعيك إذاً؟
So what are those blotches on your arms?
...وصلتني مثلهما
These are the same as theirs--
وصلتك بغسل يديك؟ كلا
You got them washing your hands? I think not.
بغسل وجهك إذاً؟ كلا أيضاً
Washing your face? Nope.
!لا يمكن أن تصلك بقع هناك بارتداء معطفك
You can't get blotches there with your coat on!
أجل، خلعتَ معطفك
Yes. You took your coat off
لحمايته من التبلل أثناء سحبك
to keep it from getting wet when you pulled
جثّة ريكا-سان المبللة
the sopping wet body out!
تبلل مرفقاك لأنّك رفعت أكمامك
Your elbows are wet because you rolled your sleeves up.
أليس ذلك صحيحاً يا إيتشييدا-سان؟
Isn't that right, Ichieda-san?
...لـ-لكن... لمَ إيتشييدا
From the fact that these were all drownings,
،مِن تمحور كلّ هذه الحوادث حول الغرق
it may have to do with Yaeko-san,
فلا بدّ أنّ للأمر علاقة بيايكو-سان
who drowned in the accident two years ago...
التي غرقت في حادثة قبل عامين
Yaeko didn't die in an accident.
لم تمت يايكو في حادثة
She was murdered...
...بل قتلها
...by Nikaido and Reika!
!نيكايدو والآنسة
The day of the storm,
يوم العاصفة
Yaeko took a lifeboat to the island to rescue Reika.
ذهبت يايكو بطوف نجاة للجزيرة لإنقاذ الآنسة
She had one life vest on, and one life vest for Reika.
كانت ترتدي سترة نجاة، ومعها أخرى للآنسة
But she was shocked when she arrived--
لكنها تفاجأت عندما وصلت الجزيرة
Nikaido was there too.
فقد كان نيكايدو هناك مع الآنسة
There were only two life vests.
معها سترتا نجاة فحسب
Are you saying--
...إ-إذاً
They didn't!
!أجل، صحيح! سرقا سترة قنجاة يايكو وأنقذا نفسيهما
wasn't wearing a vest when we found her body
ترتدي سترة نجاة عندما وجدوا جثتها
No one deserves to die.
لا أحد يستحق الموت في هذا العالم
That doesn't mean I forgive her,
لا يعني هذا أنّي أصفح عن أفعال الآنسة
but one person's death is another person's sadness.
لكنّ موت شخص يعني بؤس آخر
My own sadness is enough as it is...
حزني وحدي كافٍ... كافٍ
He attacked you too?
هاجمك أيضاً يا ران؟
Yeah...
أجل
I don't remember much because of the sleeping pills,
،لا أذكر الكثير لأنّي كنت منوّمة
but I think Shinichi came to save me...
لكن أشعر كأنّ شينتشي أتى لإنقاذي وقتها
Eh?!
!ماذا؟
Uh oh!
!تباً
But he wasn't there, was he?!
لكنه لم يذهب لذاك المنزل، أليس كذلك؟
No. It was actually Conan-kun who saved me...
أجل، كان كونان-كن من أنقذني وفقما قالوا
You were just--
...كـ-كان ذلك
But it couldn't have been that mystery nerd!
لكن يستحيل أنّه كان مهووس التحرّي ذاك
Yeah! He'd never be that thoughtful!
!أجل! يستحيل أنّ يكون ذاك الأحمق نبيهاً لهذا الحد
Alright. That's enough, already.
أنتما... توقّفا عندكما
This could be a good game!
قد تكون مباراةً رائعة
Hey, now...
...أنت
The championship flag was shredded up?!
مُزّق علم البطولة؟
This was an inside job.
كان الفاعل من الداخل
Here we go again...
...بلا سابق إنذار مُجدداً
No! You're not the real culprit!
كلا، لستَ المجرم الحقيقيّ
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Shredded Championship Flag Case."
قضيّة علم البطولة المُمزق
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Diagonal Slash.
قَطع قطري